But we we have had some of those
discussions.
>> Yeah. I mean, obviously Taylor, he's uh
he's earned the right to have as much
space as he's uh as he needs to reflect
on, you know, a long season. And we and
we we we respect him. We we give him
that. But uh but obviously you know uh
with the start of new league year coming
uh that's obviously you want as much
clarity as possible. Um so within these
next couple of weeks uh you know we
we'll make sure that we have that
clarity.
>> Yep.
>> Yeah. I mean, um, look, I I think it's,
uh, I I think it's a disservice to be
fixed and, uh, closed off on, you know,
on on anything that can help the
football team. And, um, obviously, you
know, uh, with with with your way in the
future and and the the right now. Um,
but bottom line is that, you know, we
have to make those kind of decisions to
make sure that we're in the appropriate,
you know, let's call it window from a
financial standpoint. Um, you know, to
be able to to to make the moves that we
want to move to to to make. But, uh, but
no, and I I've always been open-minded
with with that. It's just that we've
been in kind of different windows every
single year as we gone through through
this journey. So, I've been open-minded
with that for sure. How does that
approach?
>> You know, um
it doesn't really affect really I would
say the draft for for sure. Um we always
kind of take the same approach with the
draft. Uh but you know, the only thing
from a free agency standpoint, you know,
that might change certain things. Uh but
just we we we have to we have to make
sure that we're prepared. We have to
make those decisions on if we do any
kind of restructures or any kind of
stuff. But uh but that will those
decisions will affect the next decision
in terms of uh how much available
finances you'll have to spend.
>> Say that one more time.
Yeah, I mean that's
it's it's it's case by case because at
the end of the day the the the decisions
that we have to make or that we're
always fa or that we have been faced
with is that
you don't have two separate budgets,
right? It's only one budget. It's only
one pot, right? And so uh when you take
the philosophy of draft, develop and
retain, right? Well, the more you let's
let's take the word retain. Well, the
the word retain means pay. You got to
you got to pay money. All right? So, if
there's one budget, you don't have a
your own retain player budget and then a
separate external free agent budget.
Now, you can splice it up within that
one budget. this is how much you want to
use to retain their own players. This is
how much you want to use for external
free agents. But the more you retain,
that smaller that budget becomes. So,
um, but you know, um, but there's still,
um, but we we'll have flexibility to to
do some things. So, I don't think every
single year is the same. Uh, it's not
just last year we had that approach, but
it could be entirely different this
year.
>> Yeah.
Yeah, look, um, you know, I' I've been
in touch with David's, uh, his agent and
his his his representation. Uh,
obviously, look, we'd love David. Uh, we
he's a great player. Uh, we'd love to
have him. You know, I kind of want to
put last year in the rear view and just
move forward, but um, but but obviously,
you know, a player has to want to be at
a certain place as as well. So those
conversations are still fluid and then
we'll just kind of see how it goes.
>> What's that?
>> So what has he told you
>> his agent? Yeah, those are conversations
that I'll keep in house but uh but I I
would say that I've had healthy dialogue
with David at the end of the year and
I've had healthy dialogue with his
agent.
Yeah, some of it. Uh, look, they're
they're they're both doing everything
they can to get as healthy as possible.
Um, you know, we haven't put a a hard
timeline or deadline, but we've been in
regular communication with our medical
staff. Our medical staff has been in
regular communication with the player,
obviously working with them. So, I know
that they're on track to get as healthy
as possible. But uh I I think in like
another you know month or so then we'll
obviously know a lot more.
>> Well I think what what excites me is
that it wasn't um we didn't have to
endure the turnover that we had to
endure the the previous year. I mean
that's hard man. Like that's a that's a
challenge. Now when you have success you
got to be prepared for those challenges
as well. But but to um but to get to to
get the OC that we were able to get and
Drew and and and even adding, you know,
CFKA as well, but not having this
wholesale turnover. Um that was that was
kind of best of both worlds. So, um, so
I don't want to say it was better than I
expected, but, uh, but we feel really
good about having Drew come on board,
uh, as as the new OC and then still be
able to retain all the other members of
the coaching staff.
>> Talk about retaining partial.
>> Yeah, we're we're we're still having
discussions uh with that. Those are all
players that we feel are core players
that we want to keep around. They're
they're part of our foundation. Uh but
again, it it just goes back to the, you
know,
retaining, okay, that's paying and then
it's well, how much additional resources
do you have going forward? And look,
there's a lot of different, you know,
timelines and levers that we'll have at
our at our disposal, but uh but those
are all players that you ratted off that
we see as key pieces that we want to
keep around for a long time.
Yeah, we're just going to do what's
what's the best for our football team,
which we always have. You know, that's
always a subjective lens, uh, you know,
in terms of what we want to do in terms
of, you know, maybe what some what some
others may think. But, uh, but we're
we're we're just going to do the we're
just going to do the best thing
possible. um you know so there's no
there's there's nothing that we've
restricted oursel on in terms of well
we're not going to do this because we
want to do this uh so we're being very
open-minded look when you go through
what we went through uh last year like I
spoke of at the end of the season uh you
don't have a choice but to you know have
those long hard looks and be be very
open-minded to make sure that you're
looking at every possible avenue to
improve the football team
Yeah, I mean I think it's it is what it
is. I mean you are dealing with a
different let's call it athlete coming
into the NFL. Um, and that's where I
think, um, past just
acquiring the players and having the
coaches, um, that's that that's really
where those other, uh, departments on
your staff really come into play with,
you know, player engagement and player
wellness and and all of that. just to
make sure that, you know, um that they
they understand that it's different at
this level, but the resources that
they're getting at at their level, you
know, you got to have, you know,
different you got to have different
conversations with those players and but
you still have to set the same
expectations. But I I I I can't say
otherwise that it definitely is
different. Um, it's something that we've
never really experienced in the past,
but you know, all you can do is just
make the necessary adjustments and and
and adapt.
You know,
the only reason I'm going to refrain
from answering that is this because I
felt like in the past I've been a little
bit more liberal answering like the
positions of strengths, you know,
strengths, weaknesses, all that. But I
have felt in the past few years that
I'll feel one way right now and then a
month later I feel completely different.
And and I do think that's a natural
feeling. And I think that feeling should
happen because I think that's a
testament of all the work that entails
of this whole draft prep process. Um
it's it's it's not as easy as like oh
man it's a lot of defensive ends you
know available for this for this draft
right now in you know late February
early March. Well come early April that
might not be the case. And so those are
some of the things that I kind of have
spoken with you guys about in the past
of just information that's not available
that might that might shift things. So
that's the only reason why I know what
it appears to be. It appears to be a
deep crop and and I I would agree with
that, but it might not be as deep as we
think in about a month or so.
>> Detroit,
>> it was it was amazing. Um, you know, uh,
look, Detroit is such a not just sports
town, it's such a football town. You
know, I'm probably biased just because
that's the that's the business that that
that I'm in, but I just know what it did
for our city. Uh, putting our city on
the map, the small businesses that were
involved in it, uh, it was it was big
for them. So, I I would expect that, you
know, Pittsburgh can really expect the
same because I know, look, my dad played
for the Pittsburgh Steelers and so I've
always kind of followed that team from
afar and know about that franchise. I
know that they're a football town as
well, so um they should be excited.
Yeah, I mean, you know, look, uh, look,
we're we're always looking not not only
just at at the center position, but but
really every position, we want to add
more competition, add add more depth.
So, um, look, um, that that's obviously
just not just center, but offensive
line, really both sides of the of the
ball really. um that's something that's
not going to be ignored. So whether it's
through free agency through through the
draft, you know, we'll definitely look
at it.
>> Is it more of a what?
>> I think it's a little early to say that.
Uh but but I I understand your question
obviously. Um you know, it's a very
important position. uh you got to handle
a lot of information and so you know
there's uh there there's some rookies
that have been able to handle it. Uh but
you know it's it's just you just got to
find the right one and uh whether it's
day one or day two or day three if you
find the right one you can but obviously
you know the really kind of obvious way
is a player that's have already done it
already to give you a little bit more
comfort.
I think they're both a challenge. Um I
don't I don't know if there's one way
because again, you're talking about the
center position with all the information
that you have to handle. That's that
that's a big load, but then you're
talking about the left tackle position.
you know, you know, having a
right-handed quarterback and protecting
a guy's blind side. And, you know,
that's just that's the same hurdles and
and challenges as, you know, a
man-to-man corner. You know, you're
you're you're on an island and those
these edge rushers in this league,
they're they're real dudes that have
real stuff in their body. So, I would
say that they're equally as important.
Yeah, I mean you would you would think
um you would think that it it it would
be more more uh you know more active
just because you have you know some more
regime changes but I think you also got
to look at the reality is that you know
just because there's a regime change and
you know um a new coordinator new head
coach wants to start fresh uh have have
their own guys, there might not be
another guy to bring in to replace. So
um so once you think it one way on the
surface level, when you look at it
deeper and look at the availability of
okay, does this does this staff have an
ability to replace this player? Uh maybe
the player was with the coach at another
team. Well, just because the regime in
place there doesn't mean that that team
wants to trade that player. So, um, but
you know, uh, but we've been looking at
every avenue. Uh, but it it's it's a
it's a good question, but I do think
it's the reality of what the pool of
available players are.
>> Yeah, I mean, uh, Graham, I I'll start
with Graham obviously, you know, he's
still he's still under contract. Um, you
know, again, there is a the start of the
league year is a is is a real date. So,
you want to have as much clarity as
possible uh before then. So, uh
hopefully we get as much clarity as we
can before then on on Graham. And then
with with uh with with Levi and Josh,
you know, um you know, obviously um
Levi, you know, um you know, we'll be
able to bring him back and then Josh
will have a ability to bring him back as
well. There's there's still discussions
to be had about that one, but uh but
yeah, it's it's it's a possibility.
>> Say that one more time.
>> Uh those are still dialogue that we just
got to have in the future.
>> Yeah, I think that that's still a that's
I think that's a real option. Um, look,
you know, look, the the when when we
tried him out there, uh, early in in
camp, um, he wasn't doing anything wrong
that we had to move him back. We just
felt like where he was at the stage of
his career being a rookie, you know, we
felt right guard was just going to be a
little bit more of an easier acclamation
for him. And then Graham's previous
experience playing the position uh,
center in our offense was a little bit
more easier for him as well. So at that
stage, we felt like that was the right
thing. But there's still promise for
Tate to uh to to to move in that
position. But I think that's that's the
beauty of it is that those are that
that's that's flexibility that we have.
So rather if we add guard, center,
whatever, you know, I think Tate will
always be in that conversation.
Oh, yeah. I think you have to just
because look, it's it's one of the
harder things to do. Uh, but, you know,
I think you can see things from the
previous year to see kind of where the
arrow was headed. So, um, and look,
sometimes, you know, you might be wrong.
you know, you you like there's there
there's free agents in the past that I
felt like the arrow was headed down in
the wrong direction and you know, I'm
not going to say it went back up, but it
stayed pretty level. Um, so, um, but
they're they're they're hard decisions
to make, but you got to rely on kind of
what you're seeing on film currently.
Okay, now you have to make the hard
forecast of like, okay, another season.
Okay, maybe might be fine early on, but
mid to later, how's how's it how's it
going to look? And then um and then also
from a medical standpoint too, you got
to make sure um that he's intact with
that as well.
support from the psycholog.
>> Yeah, I think that's a really good
question, Jory. Um, first of all, um,
extremely sad to hear that that news and
just um give my condolences to to to his
family. Um, that was tragic to to hear.
But just saying on the topic of just
injuries from a psychological
standpoint, um, look, I think the the
the easier lens from the outside is
like, okay, a player suffered an injury,
he's he's down or he's he's he's not
available. But that's where I was
talking about um the the the the person
that asked about the NIL question and
the college players coming in. It's the
same it's the same thing with players
with injuries is that we have to put an
incredible amount of resources uh and
from a player wellness standpoint in
which we do. Um we we we have that as a
high priority player wellness in terms
of you know uh making sure that we're
keeping that player engaged and you know
making sure that that player is getting
all the services and resources available
to him because it you you're exactly
right. It's not just a physical. it it's
it's the psy psychological component
that's you probably even more important.
Um so uh but that's a high priority for
us. Um I think I I don't want to speak
for the rest of the league, but I know
just being here at the combine and all
the boards that I'm on, you know, that's
that's always a a major topic.
>> Thank you.
Hey. Hey. Hey.
[music]